Now if you have left Agnya,
Şimdi sol Agnya’nız varsa,
that means there’s possession on it.
bir sahiplenme olduğu anlamına gelir.
That means all of you have got something
Hepinizin bu tür bir şeyi var demektir,
of that kind, already you’re caught up, you’re not clean.
zaten yakalandınız, temiz değilsiniz.
What is the mantra for this, Gavin?
Bunun mantrası nedir, Gavin?
For the back Agnya,
Arka Agnya için,
Mahaganesh. Mahaganesh, Mahabhairava, correct. Now see,
Mahaganesh, Mahaganesh, Mahabhairava, doğru. Şimdi bakın,
in the brain you’ve got all these seeds of the gods
tanrıların bütün bu tohumlar beyninizde var
and they are the seeds because they’re the causal of these.
çünkü onlar tohumlar ve tohumların nedenseliği.
So the first, the causal is created
Bundan dolayı önce nedensellik yaratıldı
and then the deities are created.
ve sonra deytiler yaratıldı.
So, for example, causal of the Mother Earth is fragrance, all right
Örneğin Toprak Anne’nin nedenselğii kokudur, tamam mı?
So from fragrance comes the Mother Earth.
Böylece kokudan Toprak Anne gelir.
In the same way the causal of Brahmadeva is Hiranyagarbha,
Aynı şekilde, Brahmadeva’nın nedenseli Hiranyagarbha’dır,
all right?
tamam mı?
He’s called as Hiranyagarbha.
O’na Hiranyagarbha diye hitap edilir.
He’s the causal of Brahmadeva.
O Brahmadeva’nın nedenselidir.
Where does he stay in the brain? In the brain of the Virata
Beyinde nerede bulunur? Virata’nın beyninde
whatever deities live are the causal and ours also,
hangi deyti yaşıyorsa nedenselliğidir ve bizimkinde de,
because they’re reflected.
çünkü yansıyorlar.
So the causal ones are here
Böylece nedensel olanlar
in our brain, in our brain, in our brain.
bizim beynimizde buradadır, beynimizde, beynimizde.
At the back here,
Burada arkada,
around the Agnya,
Agnya’nın etrafında kim var?
now I give you the name,
Şimdi size ismini verdim, (yogiler: Mahaganesha)
no, around the Agnya. Agnya is Mahaganesha and Mahabhairava,
hayır, Agnya’nın etrafında. Mahagesha ve Mahabhairava
Agnya, at the back. And in front…
Agnya’dır, arkada. Ve önde…
At the back is actually Mahaganesha, just in the center.
Arkdada, aslında tam merkezde Mahaganesha var.
Just in the central point is Mahaganesha,
Tam merkez noktada, en küçük nokta olan Mahaganesha var.
Around him moves Mahabhairava, all right?
Onun etrafında Mahabhairava hareket eder, tamam mı?
And around this, the rest of it that moves is Hiranyagarbha,
Ve bunun etrafında ki geri kalan
all right? Now did you follow that?
tamam mı? Şimdi, bunu takip ettiniz mi?
So when you think, or whatever thinking you do,
Böylece, düşündüğünüzde ya da bu
through this superego, through this superego,
süper ego aracılığıyla düşünce yaparsanız,
And also otherwise, is also, who acts when you think?
Ve diğer türlü de düşündüğünüzde kim hareket ediyor?
Is Hiranyagarbha. Isn't it.
Hiranyagarbha. Değil mi
This is Swadishthana,
Bu Swadishthana,
we call it, this is Swadishthana chakra around it, all right?
dediğimiz, etrafında ki Swadishthana çakra, tamam mı?
So Swadishthana is divided into left and right.
Yani, Swadishthana sol ve sağ olarak ayrılmıştır.
Left Swadishthana is Hiranyagarbha
Sol Swadishthana Hiranyagarbha
and right Swadishthana is also Hiranyagarbha,
ve sağ Swadishthana da Hiranyagarbha’dır,
at the back here.
burada arka tarafta.
So now to point out first of all, at the back, if you move,
Şimdi, her şeyden önce resmetmek için arkada eğer hareket ederseniz
is Mahaganesha.
Mahaganesha’dır.
Around him moves Bhairava, who protects Mahaganesha.
Mahaganesha'yı koruyan Bhairava etrafında hareket eder.
Around it moves, now who? Hiranyagarbha, at the back.
Etrafında hareket eden, kim? Hiranyagarbha, arkada.
But Hiranyagarbha has left and right side while Bhairava
Ancak, Hiranyagarbha’nın sol ve sağ tarafı var iken Bhairava
and Ganesha, they move on each other. Did you follow that point?
Ganesha birbirleri üzerinde hareket ediyorlar.
Now in front, in the center here,
Bu noktayı takip ettiniz mi?
is who? Kartikeya, in the center;
Şimdi, önde burada, merkezde kim var? Kartikeya, merkezde.
Christ is in the center, in the
İsa merkezde,
center itself where the optic chiasma is.
merkezin kendisinde optik kiazmanın olduğu yerde.
Here outside is Kartikeya. What is Kartikeya?
Burada, dışında Kartikeya. Kartikeya nedir?
Kartikeya is the protector of Christ. Around Kartikeya,
Kartikeya, İsa’nın koruyucusu. Kartikeya’nın etrafında ki
they’re all protectors of Christ, moves who?
hepsi İsa’nın koruyucularıdır. Kim hareket eder?
Now, who is Mahabhairava’s counterpart?
Şimdi, Mahabhairava’nın emsali kim?
And around that, what does move? Ekadasha Rudra.
Ve bunun etrafında, ne hareket ediyor? Ekadasha Rudra.
The movement of Ekadasha Rudra
Ekadasha Rudra’nın hareketi dairesel değildir, böyle hareket eder.
is not circular, it is move like that.
dairesel değildir, böyle hareket eder.
It moves like that. Or you can say, move like that.
Bu şekilde hareket eder.
Now what is Ekadasha Rudra? Let us see.
Şimdi, Ekadasha Rudra nedir? Bakalım.
Can you give the names? Of Ekadasha. Take one by one.
İsimleri söyleyebilir misiniz? Ekadasha’nın. Tek tek söyleyin.
Buddha,
Buddha,
right? Mahavira.
tamam mı? Mahavira.
Then Christ, then Mahabhairava.
Sonra İsa, sonra Mahabhairava.
How many of them, four.
Kaç tanesi, dört.
Then Mahaganesha, five.
Sonra, Mahaganesha beş.
Did I say Bhairava?
Bhairava dedim mi?
Again, again say it one by one, Buddha,
Tekrar, tek tek tekrar edelim, Buddha,
Mahavira, Christ, Mahaganesha, Mahabhairava.
Mahavira, İsa, Mahaganesha, Mahabhairava.
All right, this is very clear cut for you
Tamam, bu sizin için çok kolay anlaşılır,
because just now I’ve told all of them.
çünkü size hepsini söyledim.
Buddha, Mahavira, Christ.
Buddha, Mahavira, İsa.
Then, what else, four are left, four are still left.
Sonra, başka, dört tane kaldı, hala dört tane kaldı.
Mahahanumana, you didn’t tell? Mahahanumana, how much it is now?
Mahahanumana, söylemedin mi? Mahahanumana, şimdi ne kadar oldu?
Three left, no four are left, four, now what are these four?
Üç kaldı, hayır dördü kaldı, dört, şimdi bu dördü ne?
Mahabhairava, two, Buddha, Mahavira. Four, now, Kartikeya.
Mahabhairava, iki, Buddha, Mahavira.
Kartikeya, Ganesha, sixth.
Ganesha, altı.
Christ, seventh. Now four more are left,
İsa, yedinci. Dört tane daha kaldı,
now who are the four more,
şimdi bu dördü kimler, bakalım. Çay alabilir miyim?
Pat, come along.
Pat, buraya gel.
You’ve done lot of reading.
Çok fazla okudun.
Try to, I have written it down into something, eleven of these.
Deneyin, bir şeyin içine yazdım, on bir tanesini.
yogini: Hiranyagarbha
Yogini: Hiranyagarbha
Brahmadeva,
Brahmadeva,
Hiranyagarbha, correct.
Hiranyagarbha, doğru.
Vishnu, Narayana,
Vishnu, Narayana,
Lakshmi Narayana, how much it is.
Lakshmi Narayana, kaç oldu oldu?
Shiva, Parvati, everyone.
Shiva, Parvati, herbiri.
Shiva and Shakti, all right?
Shiva ve Shakti, tamam mı? Bitti.
Eleven of them.
On biri.
Lakshmi Narayana is one, Brahmadeva Saraswati is...
Lakshmi Narayana bir, Brahmadeva Saraswati…
Shiva Parvati, as two.
Shiva Parvati iki olarak.
All eleven are there. Why Shiva and Parvati?
On birinin tamamı orada. Neden Shiva ve Parvati?
Two have to be taken because Shiva is the Guru,
İkiside anılmalı çünkü Shiva Guru’dur,
Parvati is the Shakti.
Parvati de Shakti’dir.
the beginning of the trouble starts
sorunun başlangıcı başlar (sorunun başlangıcındasınız demektir,)
There Shiva is to be taken as Guru,
Orada Shiva Guru olarak anılmalı,
Shiva is Guru, Shiva is the one
Shiva Guru’dur, Shiva bizim Guru’muz olan.
who is our Guru. He is our spirit.
O bizim ruhumuzdur.
But he’s not the spirit
Ancak o koruyan ruh değildir
that protects because spirit needs no protection.
çünkü ruhun korumaya ihtiyacı yoktur.
Whom do you protect then, also.
Peki, o zaman kimi koruyorsunuz?
So when you protect,
Böylece siz koruduğunuzda,
you protect the spirit but what protects it
ruhu korursunuz ancak koruyan şey
is the Guru personality which is Shiva,
Guru kişiliğidir, Shiva’dır,
which is Shiva actually.
gerçekte Shiva’dır.
Did you get that?
Anladınız mı?
Now you might say how is Shiva is
Şimdi siz, Shiva nasıl
“Guru Brahma, Guru Vishnu, Guru Devom, Maheshwara,
“Guru Brahma, Guru Vishnu, Guru Devom, Maheshwara,
Guru Sakshat, Parabrahma, Tasmai Shri Guruveh Namah.”
Guru Sakshat, Parabrahma, Tasmai Shri Guruveh Namah” oluyor diyebilirsiniz.
Because Guru means a person who is
Çünkü Guru, tamamıyla
full of Gurutwakashan, is weight, is the gravity.
Gurutwakashan olan bir kişi, ağırlık, yer çekimi demek.
Person who is with gravity, which has some sense,
Yer çekimi olan, sağduyusu olan,
which is density,
yoğunluğu olan,
which is our spirit. Otherwise we have no density, we’re useless.
ruhumuz olan kişi. Aksi halde yoğunluğumuz yoktur, işe yaramazız.
Our spirit goes away, we float in the air as bhoots.
Ruhumuz gider, biz havada boot olarak süzülürüz.
So the Guru is everything.
Bu yüzden Guru her şeydir.
Today I’ve called you here to tell you how to become a Guru.
Bugün sizi nasıl Guru olabileceğinizi anlatmak için buraya çağırdım
So that’s why I’ve given you this introduction. Is it clear to you?
Bu yüzden size bu tanıtımı verdim. Açık mı?
All right let Me know. Now…
Tamam, Bana bilgi verin. Şimdi…
See that? (not clear) Just laugh at yourself.
Gördünüz mü? Sadece kendinize gülün.
With all your knowledge of how many years I’ve been talking to you,
Tüm bilginizle, kaç yıldır sizinle konuştuğuma bakın,
look at this, this is the point.
buna bakın, işte mesele bu.
How Mother raising your kundalini just like that.
Anneniz, Kundalini'nizi nasıl böyle yükseltir.
Do I tell you something?
Size bir şey söylüyor muyum?
You all have gone to the wrong gurus, you have done,
Hepiniz yanlış gurulara gittiniz, şunu yaptınız,
because…nothing of the kind. Just because
çünkü (anlaşılmıyor), böyle bir şey yok.
you’re not set here,
Sadece buraya gelmediniz diye.
it’s the Ekadasha Rudra on your forehead,
Yanlış gurunun önünde eğilirseniz, alnınızdaki Ekadasha Rudra'dır.
If you bow before any wrong guru.
Bununla Ekadasha Rudra'nız (anlaşılmıyor).
Sahaja Yoga is very simple you know?
Sahaja Yoga çok basit, biliyor musunuz?
If you put your glass upside down...(not clear)
Bardağınızı baş aşağı koyarsanız, (anlaşılmıyor)
if you put it like this, it is exposed to the...(not clear).
içeri girmez, böyle koyarsanız, (anlaşılmıyor)…maruz kalır.
Sahaja Yoga is so simple,
Sahaja Yoga çok basit,
do you follow that point?
bu noktayı takip ediyor musunuz?
So we reach one conclusion, by mental understanding
Böylece bir sonuca varıyoruz, zihinsel anlayışla
you cannot understand Sahaja Yoga.
Sahaja Yoga'yı anlayamazsınız.
So as a guru
Peki, bir guru olarak
what should you have?
neye sahip olmalısınız?
I’ve made a promise. That’s different.
Bir söz verdim. Bu farklı.
Yogini is asking a question...
– Yogini bir soru soruyor  (anlaşılmıyor)
You are telling like this,
Böyle söylüyorsun,
if I say that, “What is the test of,
"Bir Guru’nun testi nedir?"
say, guru?” Do you say that it should not become artificial?
Yapay olmaması gerektiğini mi söylüyorsun?
Now let’s see again quite straight forward, what is the question?
Bakalım, tekrar, oldukça basit, soru nedir?
No, no, what is the question?
Hayır, hayır, soru nedir?
Now try to remember.
Şimdi hatırlamaya çalışın.
Yogi: What should we have? Shri Mataji: Not at all!
Yogi: Neye sahip olmalıyız?
So what is the question, let's see exactly.
Soru nedir, tam olarak görelim. Kesinlikle.
Yogini: How do you clearing the catch from seing a false guru?
Sahte bir guruyu görmekten yakalanmayı (catch) nasıl temizlersin?
This is another question, but the question I asked is:
Bu başka bir soru ama sorduğum soru şu:
then what must a guru do?
bir guru ne yapmalı?
The thing I said, by discussion
Söylediğim şey, ayırt ederek
Sahaja Yoga doesn’t work out then what should we do?
Sahaja Yoga çalışmıyorsa o zaman ne yapmalıyız?
I asked the question what should we do?
Ne yapmalıyız sorusunu sordum
Make it simple always
Her zaman basitleştirin,
related to your Mother, you’ll get the answer. Hah! All right?
Annenizle ilgili olarak, cevabı alacaksınız. Hah! Tamam mı?
To neutralize the old guru
Kötü bir guru olan eski guruyu
who has been a bad guru
etkisiz hale getirmek için
you have to surrender to the real guru.
gerçek guruya teslim olmalısınız.
If your guru is the real guru
Gurunuz gerçek guruysa,
then you surrender to the Mother of your real guru.
gerçek gurunuzun Annesine teslim olursunuz.
Because your real guru is also surrendered to Me.
Çünkü gerçek gurunuz da Bana teslim oldu.
So all gurus are to be surrendered at the lotus feet of your Mother
Bu yüzden tüm gurular Annenizin lotus ayaklarına teslim edilecek.
Then if it is Brahma, Vishnu, Mahesha, Shiva, Krishna,
Öyleyse Brahma, Vishnu, Mahesha, Shiva, Krishna,
Christ, anyone of them also,
İsa, bunlardan herhangi biri, üstelik
Ekadasha still is more than your Mother’s...
Ekadesha da hala Annenizin (anlaşılmıyor) den daha fazlasıdır.
It is very difficult
Çok zor
because we want to stick on to something,
çünkü bir şeye, hatta gerçek guruya bağlı kalmak istiyoruz.
even the real guru. Christ is a real guru
Mesih gerçek bir gurudur ama
Christ you know of is to be also surrendered at the lotus feet
bildiğiniz İsa aynı zamanda Annenizin lotus ayaklarına
of your Mother because we also know that.
teslim olmaktır, çünkü bunu da biliyoruz.
Brahma, Vishnu, Mahesha, all of them are My servants.
Brahma, Vishnu, Mahesha, hepsi Benim kullarım.
Adi Shakti is the Mother.
Adi Shakti Annedir.
She’s the Mother of all the gurus,
O, tüm gurularının,
of all the prophets, of all the incarnations, of all the deities.
tüm peygamberlerin, tüm enkarnasyonların, tüm deytilerin Annesidir.
After Her, only Parabrahma is created, after that only Parabrahma.
Ondan sonra sadece Parabrahma yaratılır sadece Parabrahma yaratılır
So when you have got someone like that to surrender,
Bu yüzden, teslim olmak için böyle birisine sahipseniz,
is the real problem, is a maya.
gerçek sorun, mayadır.
That is the biggest problem because you’ve got somebody so easily.
En büyük sorun bu çünkü çok kolay bir şekilde birisine sahipsiniz.
Arjuna was a great warrior till the war started,
Arjuna savaş başlayana kadar harika bir savaşçıydı
and somebody was a great swimmer when he came to the ocean.
ve kimisi de okyanusa geldiğinde harika bir yüzücüydü.
Allow your mind to do the work,
Zihninizin işi yapmasına izin verin,
allow your mind.
zihninize izin verin.
So to be the highest guru we’ve to be completely surrendered.
Bu yüzden en yüksek guru olmak için tamamen teslim olmalıyız.
Now when you’re surrendered,
Şimdi teslim olduğunuzda
you don’t doubt.
şüphe etmeyiniz.
For Me this finger is completely surrendered, say,
Benim için, bu parmak tamamen teslim oldu,
to My body, it doesn’t doubt My body.
Bedenime diyelim, vücudumdan şüphe duymuyor.
Supposing I’m pressing and
Diyelim ki bastırıyorum ve
it receives the information that you’re doing that
bunu sizin yaptığınızın bilgisini alıyor,
she informs the brain
beyni bilgilendiriyor
and informs the body that I’m doing that.
ve vücuda bunu benim yaptığımı bildiriyor.
all the fingers act
tüm parmaklar hareket ediyor
and all the power flows there,
ve tüm güç orada akıyor,
the energy flows there where the finger is hurt.
enerji oraya parmağın yaralandığı yere akıyor.
So when you are surrendered
Böylece teslim olduğunuzda
there is no question of individualism.
bireysellik söz konusu değildir.
Those people who think of any kind of individualism
Her türlü bireyciliği düşünenler,
are going to go out of the circulation of Sahaja Yoga.
Sahaja Yoga'nın dolaşımından çıkacaklar.
From the beginning, I’ve told you many a time if we
En başından beri,
take out all those people who want to
bireyselliklerini herhangi bir şekilde iddia etmek isteyen
assert their individualism of any kind.
tüm insanları çıkarırsak diye size birçok kez söyledim.
You see,
Görüyorsunuz,
this is a branch, all right, you can see here.
bu bir dal, tamam, burada görebilirsiniz.
In the last stage, I use the same analogy better and better.
Son aşamada, aynı benzetmeyi daha iyi ve daha iyi kullanıyorum.
Outside is the same, all right?
Dışarıda aynı, tamam mı?
If inside and outside is the same and the rest is (not clear).
İçeride ve dışarıda aynıysa ve gerisi (net değil).
If this has to become this, what has to .
Eğer bunun bu olması gerekiyorsa, ne olmalıdır (net değil).
This myth has to go, all right?
Bu efsane gitmeli, tamam mı?
This myth has to vanish.
Bu efsanenin yok olmak zorunda.
So this myth is based on what,
Yani bu efsane sadece ego ve süper egomuza dayanır.
Which are actually the end result
Bunlar aslında tüm saçmalıklarımızın sonucudur.
In a sense,
Bir anlamda,
all this has to go, vanish, it doesn’t exist at all, that is the way you surrender.
bunların hepsi gitmesi gerek, yok olmalı, hiç yok,
Indulgence
Hoşgörü
You cannot be a guru unless and until at least
Ona açık olmadıkça, bu geliyor ve gidiyor,
that’s coming and going, but supposing you’re like this.
ancak diyelim böylesiniz en azından ona açık olmadıkça
two of them.
hatta iki tane aptal.
They went inside the restaurant to have something.
Bir şeyler yemek için restorana gittiler.
They sat down on a table
Bir masaya oturdular
and they saw a glass like this.
ve böyle bir bardak gördüler.
They said, “What sort of a glass is this, it has no mouth.”
Dediler ki, “Bu nasıl bir bardak, ağzı yok.”
So they called the bearer and said,
Bu yüzden servis yapanı çağırdılar ve
“See we can’t have food unless and until it has a mouth, take it back.”
“Ağzı olana kadar yemek yiyemeyeceğiz, bunu geri alın” dediler.
They said, “What sort of a glass is this, it has no water?”
Dediler ki, “Bu nasıl bir bardak, suyu yok?”
Because (not clear)
Çünkü (net değil).
But when you’re surrendered the mouth and bottom is... luckily its…
Ama teslim olduğunuzda ağız ve dip (anlaşılmıyor).
That surrendering is to be achieved
Neyse ki onun (anlaşılmıyor).
if you’re going to be the gurus.
Eğer guru olacaksanız, bu teslimiyet sağlanacaktır.
This is all mental, how do you open?
Şimdi, söyleyeceğim çok kişisel bir şey olduğundan not edin. (Bant kesildi)
Have a bandhan.
Bunların hepsi zihinsel, nasıl açılır? Kendinize bandan verin.
How many times you give yourself bandhan?
Kendinize kaç kere bandan veriyorsunuz?
Before sleeping,
Uyumadan önce,
after getting up, then namaskar to your Mother,
kalktıktan sonra Annenize namaskar,
touching My feet, very important,
Ayaklarıma dokunmak, çok önemli,
not to come on to the Agnya, supposed to correct.
Agnya'ya gelmemek, düzeltmesi gerekiyor.
Even sitting down there I’m catching.
Orada otururken bile yakalandım (catch).
Actually just do it now.
Aslında şimdi yapın.
No, again.
Tekrar
Do it on both the feet, again you try.
her iki ayağa yapın, tekrar deneyin.
First right and then left. Ah! See now.
Önce sağ sonra sol. Hah! Şimdi bakın.
It’s not mental, this is the point I’m bringing you.
Zihinsel değil, işte sizi getirdiğim nokta bu.
It is not mental, now this is (not clear).
Zihinsel değil, şimdi mesele bu (anlaşılmıyor).
you all become mentally alert
Hepiniz zihinsel olarak uyanık olursunuz (net değil).
See you must surrender to the Mother and...open your heart.
Bakın, Anneye teslim olmalısın ve (anlaşılmıyor) kalbinizi açın.
So, sweetness is open your heart…not clear.
Böylece, tatlılık kalbinizi açıyor… net değil.
When others come we don’t tell them this is how we open our heart. Don’t tell them.
Diğerleri geldiğinde onlara kalbimizi böyle açtığımızı söylemiyoruz. Onlara söylemeyin… (anlaşılmıyor)
How you open your left Vishuddhi, just say, “Mother I am not guilty.
… Sol Vishuddhi'yi nasıl açarsın, sadece “Anne ben suçlu değilim.
Mother I’m not guilty. Mother I’m not guilty.”
Anne suçlu değilim. Anne ben suçlu değilim ”.
Too much thinking, too much talking is bad.
Çok fazla düşünmek çok fazla konuşmak kötüdür.
Not talking, not thinking is bad.
Hiç konuşmamak hiç düşünmemek kötüdür.
But little thinking, little talking is good.
Ama azıcık düşünmek, azıcık konuşmak iyidir.